Dr. Po-Hsun Tseng

6+ years experience of large-scale software development with C programming on the Linux system throughout my Ph.D. journey.

Seeking a challenging and rewarding opportunity with low-level system programming (eg. device driver, Linux kernel, CPU architecture) to apply my skills at a fabless company.



CONTACT

zengbs@gmail.com

+886 966 587 832

Hsinchu, Taiwan

https://github.com/zengbs

SKILLS

Programming

Bash scripting
System programming

CUDA Python

Operating System

Linux - user

Linux - kernel
Architecture

ARM architecture

Software & Tools

Git Vim Gdb

Valgrind

Languages

Chinese (native)

English - writing

English - speaking

English - listening

English - reading

EDUCATION

1 08/2016 - 06/2022

National Taiwan University, Taiwan

Ph.D. in Computational Physics

- Developed and implemented a new algorithm to reduce numerical error by a factor of 10^6 compared to conventional one. See Fig. 16 in (https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.11130).
- A main contributor of the gammer-project on GitHub. (https://github.com/gamer-project/gamer/graphs/contributors)
- Designed a new approach to further promote the robustness of the GAMMER. (https://github.com/gamer-project/gamer/pull/60/files)
- Worked on improving the GAMER collaborated with Dr. Chiueh/Dr. Schive.
 See the Section References.
- Built and maintained the Linux cluster, NFS, and NIS in our lab.

WORK HISTORY

12/2014 - 01/2016

♥ TDK corporation, Singapore

Circuit designer

Design the circiut of surface acoustic wave(SAW) filters

6 08/2013 - 08/2014

Military Service

EDUCATION

1 09/2011 - 07/2013

National Taiwan University, Taiwan

M.Sc. in Physics

M 09/2006 - 07/2011

B.Sc. in Mathematics

SOFT SKILLS

Nonverbal communication

Active listening

Open mindedness

Patience

Mutual respect

Teamwork

Brainstorming

Collaboration

GENERAL SKILLS

Numerical algorithm

Large-scale project

cscope

makefile

GNU autotools

PUBLICATIONS

An adaptive mesh, GPU-accelerated, and error minimized special relativistic hydrodynamics code

Po-Hsun Tseng, Hsi-Yu Schive, Tzihong Chiueh

Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society Vol. 504, pp. 3298-3315
https://arxiv.org/abs/2012.11130

The symmetry problem of the Fermi and eROSITA bubbles: A proof-of-concept study
Po-Hsun Tseng, Hsiang-Yi Karen Yang, Hsi-Yu Schive, Tzihong Chiueh

2022 preprint

TALKS

 An adaptive-mesh, GPU-accelerated, and optimally error-controlled special relativistic hydrodynamics code Oral (remote), American Center for Physics College Park, U.S.A

Mar. 2021

A new and accurate code for simulating special relativistic hydrodynamics
 Oral, Annual Meeting of the Physical Society of Taiwan, NPTU.

Feb. 2020

REFERENCES

- Please send an appointment letter to request a call. 😃
- Dr. Tzihong Chiueh

Distinguished Professor, Institute of Astrophysics, National Taiwan University

- ▼ Taipei 10617, Taiwan
- chiuehth@phys.ntu.edu.tw
- +886 2 3366 8628
- Dr. Hsi-Yu Schive

Assistant Professor, Institute of Astrophysics, National Taiwan University

- ▼ Taipei 10617, Taiwan
- hyschive@phys.ntu.edu.tw
- **** +886 2 3366 8644
- Dr. Hsiang-Yi Karen Yang

Assistant Professor, Institute of Astronomy, National Tsing Hua University

- Hsinchu 30013, Taiwan
- hyang@phys.nthu.edu.tw
- **4886** 3 574 2953